A Guide to the Virginia Attorney General's correspondence and letter books, 1898-1920
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Virginia Attorney General's correspondence and letter books, 1898-1920
The Library of Virginia
44018
8.25 cu. ft. (24 boxes) and 16 volumes
Virginia. Office of the Attorney General
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Original transfer information is unavailable. This collection was retroactively accessioned.
Historical Information
The Office of the Attorney General originated in medieval England. While representing the king in his courts, the Attorney General gradually assumed the role of legal advisor to the government and all its agencies. In Virginia, the first Attorney General was commissioned in 1643. The Declaration of Independence in 1776 ended the Attorney General's connection with royal authority, but the state constitution adopted that year continued the office under the auspices of the General Assembly. The constitution adopted in 1851 provided for the popular election of the Attorney General, rendering him independent of all three branches of government. The Attorney General is elected to a four-year term in office and is eligible for reelection.
Scope and Content
Contains incoming correspondence files and outgoing letter books from the administrations of Attorneys General Andrew J. Montague, William A. Anderson, and Samuel W. Williams.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series:
Series I. Correspondence files, 1898-1920
Series II. Letter books, 1898-1910
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence files, 1898-1920., Extent: 8.25 cu. ft. (24 boxes) (Box 1-24.)
  Contains mostly incoming letters to the Virginia Attorney General, as well as a limited number of outgoing letters. The correspondence files span the administrations of Attorneys General, Andrew J. Montague (1898-1902), William A. Anderson (1902-1910), Samuel W. Williams (1910-1914), John G. Pollard (1914-1918), and John R. Saunders (1918-1934). Very little of the correspondence dates from the Pollard and Saunders administrations. The correspondence is comprised of requests for official opinions on a variety of legal matters including voting rights, property disputes, and criminal prosecution. Some communication between the Attorney General, the Governor, Commonwealth's Attorneys, and other state agency officials can be found here. However, most of the correspondence is in the form of letters from private lawyers and citizens with specific questions about various aspects of Virginia law. Located at the end of this collection are folders of cancelled checks, miscellaneous documents and subject files. Several notable subject files relate to a state case against the Jamestown Jockey Club for illegal gambling on horse races.
  Arranged chronologically by year, and then by letter of the alphabet. However, there is no particular arrangement of the correspondence within the folder or folders for each letter.
  - 1898 S-Y. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1899 A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1899 B. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1899 B. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1899 C. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1899 C. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1899 D. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1899 E. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1899 F. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1899 G. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1899 G. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1899 H. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1899 H. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1899 I-J. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1899 K-L. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1899 M. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1899 M. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1899 N-O. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1899 P. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1899 R. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1899 S. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1899 S. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1899 T-V. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1899 W. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1899 W. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1899 Y. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1900 A. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1900 B. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1900 B. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1900 B. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1900 C. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1900 C. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1900 D. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1900 E. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1900 F. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1900 G. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1900 H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1900 H. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1900 I-J. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1900 K. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1900 L. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1900 M. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1900 M. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1900 N. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1900 O. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1900 P. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1900 Q. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1900 R. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1900 R. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1900 S. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1900 S. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1900 T-V. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1900 W. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1900 W. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1900 Y-Z. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1901 A. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1901 B. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1901 B. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1901 C. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1901 C. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1901 D. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1901 E. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1901 F. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1901 G. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1901 H. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1901 I-J. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1901 K. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1901 L. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1901 M. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1901 M. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1901 N-O. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1901 P. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1901 Q-R. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1901 S. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1901 T-V. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1901 W. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1901 Y. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1902 A. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1902 B. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1902 B. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1902 B. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1902 C. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1902 C. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1902 C. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1902 C. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1902 D. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1902 D. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1902 E. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1902 F. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1902 G. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1902 G. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1902 H. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1902 H. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1902 I-J. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1902 K. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1902 L. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1902 L. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1902 M. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1902 M. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1902 M. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1902 N. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1902 O. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1902 P. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1902 P. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 1902 Q-R. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1902 S. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1902 S. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1902 T. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1902 W. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1902 W. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1902 V. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1902 Y-Z. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1903 A. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1903 B. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1903 B. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1903 B. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1903 C. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1903 C. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1903 C. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1903 C. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1903 D. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 1903 E. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1903 F. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1903 G. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1903 G. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1903 H. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1903 H. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1903 J. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1903 K. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1903 L. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1903 M. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1903 M. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1903 M. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1903 N-O. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1903 P. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1903 P. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 1903 Q. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1903 R. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1903 S. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1903 S. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 1903 T. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1903 V. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1903 W. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1903 W. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1903 W. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1903 Y-Z. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1904 A. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1904 A. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1904 B. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1904 B. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1904 B. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1904 B. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1904 B. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1904 C. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1904 C. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1904 C. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1904 C. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 1904 D. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1904 E. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1904 F. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1904 G. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1904 G. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1904 G. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1904 H. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1904 H. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1904 H. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1904 I. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1904 J. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1904 J. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1904 K. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1904 L. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 1904 L. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 1904 M. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 1904 M. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 1904 M. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1904 M. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1904 N. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1904 O. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1904 P. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1904 P. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1904 Q. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1904 R. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1904 R. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1904 S. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1904 S. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 1904 T. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 1904 T. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 1904 U-V. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 1904 W. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - 1904 W. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - 1904 W. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - 1904 W. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - 1904 Y. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - 1905 A. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1905 A. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1905 B. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1905 B. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1905 B. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1905 C. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1905 C. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1905 C. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1905 D. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1905 E. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1905 F. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1905 G. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 1905 G. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - 1905 H. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - 1905 H. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - 1905 H. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - 1905 I. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - 1905 J. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - 1905 K. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1905 L. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1905 M. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1905 M. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1905 M. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1905 N. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1905 O. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1905 P. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1905 P. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 1905 P. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1905 Q. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1905 R. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 1905 S. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 1905 S. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - 1905 S. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - 1905 T. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - 1905 T. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - 1905 U-V. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1905 W. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1905 W. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1905 W. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1905 Y. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1906 A. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1906 B. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1906 B. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1906 B. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1906 C. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1906 C. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1906 C. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 1906 C. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 1906 D. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 1906 E. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - 1906 E. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 1906 F. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - 1906 G. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1906 G. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1906 H. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1906 H. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1906 I. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1906 J. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1906 K. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1906 L. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1906 L. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1906 M. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 1906 M. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1906 M. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1906 M. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 1906 N. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 1906 O. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1906 P. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1906 P. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - 1906 R. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1906 R. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1906 S. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1906 S. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1906 S. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1906 S. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 1906 T. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 1906 U-V. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 1906 W. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - 1906 W. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 1906 W. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 1906 Y-Z; unknown. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - 1907 A. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 1907 B. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - 1907 B. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - 1907 B. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - 1907 B. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - 1907 C. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1907 C. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1907 C. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1907 D. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1907 E. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 1907 E. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 1907 E. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - 1907 F. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - 1907 G. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 1907 G. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - 1907 H. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - 1907 H. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - 1907 H. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - 1907 H. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - 1907 H. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - 1907 I. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - 1907 J. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - 1907 K. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1907 L. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 1907 M. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 1907 M. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 1907 M. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1907 M. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 1907 M. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 1907 N-O. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 1907 P. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - 1907 P. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - 1907 Q-R. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 1907 S. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - 1907 S. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - 1907 S. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - 1907 S. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - 1907 S. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - 1970 T. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - 1907 T. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - 1907 V. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 1907 W. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 1907 W. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 1907 W. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1907 W. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 1907 Y-Z. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 1908 A. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - 1908 B. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - 1908 B. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - 1908 B. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - 1908 B. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - 1908 C. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - 1908 C. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - 1908 D. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - 1908 D. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - 1908 E. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - 1908 E. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - 1908 F. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 1908 G. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 1908 H. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 1908 H. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - 1908 H. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 1908 H. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - 1908 I-J. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 1908 K. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - 1908 L. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 1908 L. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - 1908 M. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - 1908 M. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - 1908 M. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - 1908 M. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - 1908 N. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - 1908 O. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - 1908 P. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 1908 P. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1908 R. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1908 R. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 1908 S. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1908 S. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 1908 S. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1908 T. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1908 T. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 1908 T. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 1908 W. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - 1908 W. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - 1908 W. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - 1908 W. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - 1908 Y-Z. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - 1909 A. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1909 B. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 1909 B. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 1909 B. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1909 C. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1909 C. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 1909 D. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 1909 D. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - 1909 E. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 1909 E. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - 1909 F. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - 1909 G. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - 1909 H. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - 1909 H. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - 1909 H. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - 1909 J. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - 1909 K. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - 1909 L. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1909 L. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1909 M. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1909 M. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1909 M. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1909 N. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1909 O. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - 1909 P. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - 1909 P. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - 1909 R. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - 1909 S. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - 1909 S. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - 1909 S. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - 1909 T. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - 1909 T. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - 1909 U-V. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - 1909 W. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1909 W. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1909 W. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1909 W. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1909 Y. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - 1910 B. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 1910 D-E. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - 1910 H-L. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - 1910 M. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - 1910 O-S. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - 1910 T-W. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - 1911. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - 1912. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - 1913 A-C. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - 1913 D-H. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - 1913 K-L. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - 1913 M-R. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - 1913 S. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - 1913 T. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - 1913 W-Y. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Cancelled checks, 1911-1912. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Commonwealth vs Jamestown Jockey Club, 1911. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth vs Jamestown Jockey Club, 1912-1916. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth vs Jamestown Jockey Club (court papers), 1911. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth vs Jamestown Jockey Club (court papers), 1911. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth vs Jamestown Jockey Club (court papers), 1911. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous documents and opinions, 1902-1912; undated. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Portrait of Mrs. Elvira B. Taylor, 1917-1920. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - W.H. Robertson, Special Commissioner vs Commonwealth, 1919-1920. (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Series II. Letter books (outgoing), 1898-1910., Extent: 16 volumes.
  Letter books contain only outgoing correspondence written by the Attorney General. The books span the administrations of Attorneys General Andrew J. Montague (1898-1902) and William A. Anderson (1902-1910). Most of the letters answer questions posed by citizens and government entities regarding topics such as the Code of Virginia, the validity of taxes and local ordinances, and constutional law. Some letters also pertain to specific court cases.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1898 January-November.
  - 1898 November-1900 April.
  - 1900 April-1901 December.
  - 1902 January-August.
  - 1902 August-1903 April.
  - 1903 April-November.
  - 1903 November-1904 June.
  - 1904 June-1905 March.
  - 1905 March-September.
  - 1905 September-1906 April.
  - 1906 April-November.
  - 1906 November-1907 July.
  - 1907 July-1908 April.
  - 1908 April-1909 February.
  - 1909 February-1910 January.
  - 1910 January-March.